{
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "What is the capital city of Pakistan?",
      "options": ["Islamabad", "Lahore", "Rawalpindi", "Karachi"],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which river is the longest in Pakistan?",
      "options": ["Jhelum River", "Chenab River", "Ravi River", "Indus River"],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which mountain range is located in the northern part of Pakistan?",
      "options": ["Karakoram Range", "Himalayas", "Andes", "Rocky Mountains"],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Which city is known as the 'City of Lights' in Pakistan?",
      "options": ["Karachi", "Islamabad", "Lahore", "Multan"],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "Who is considered the national poet of Pakistan?",
      "options": [
        "Faiz Ahmed Faiz",
        "Allama Iqbal",
        "Mirza Ghalib",
        "Fahmida Riaz"
      ],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 10
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the highest mountain in Pakistan and the second-highest in the world?",
      "options": ["Mount Everest", "Annapurna", "K2", "Nanga Parbat"],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Pakistani cricketer is known as the 'Rawalpindi Express'?",
      "options": ["Wasim Akram", "Imran Khan", "Waqar Younis", "Shoaib Akhtar"],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the famous ancient archaeological site in Pakistan, also known as the 'Mound of the Dead'?",
      "options": ["Harappa", "Swat Valley", "Mohenjo-Daro", "Taxila"],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the highest battlefield in the world, located in Pakistan-occupied Kashmir?",
      "options": [
        "K2 Base Camp",
        "Nanga Parbat",
        "Concordia",
        "Siachen Glacier"
      ],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the name of the famous ancient trade route that connected the East and West, passing through parts of present-day Pakistan?",
      "options": ["Amber Road", "Salt Route", "Incense Route", "Silk Road"],
      "correctOption": 3,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Which city in Pakistan is known for its traditional truck art and is often called the 'City of Flowers'?",
      "options": ["Faisalabad", "Peshawar", "Quetta", "Rawalpindi"],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the first female Prime Minister of Pakistan?",
      "options": [
        "Hina Rabbani Khar",
        "Benazir Bhutto",
        "Fatima Jinnah",
        "Asma Jahangir"
      ],
      "correctOption": 1,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the Pakistani pilot responsible for downing and capturing the Indian pilot, Wing Commander Abhinandan Varthaman, during a military confrontation in 2019?",
      "options": [
        "Group Captain Ali",
        "Wing Commander Ahmed Shah",
        "Squadron Leader Hassan Siddiqui",
        "Flight Lieutenant Bilal"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Which ancient civilization, dating back over 4,000 years, developed in the region of what is now Pakistan?",
      "options": [
        "Indus Valley Civilization",
        "Babylonian Civilization",
        "Egyptian Civilization",
        "Mayan Civilization"
      ],
      "correctOption": 0,
      "points": 20
    },
    {
      "question": "Which Pakistani scientist is often referred to as the 'Father of the Pakistani Bomb' for his significant contributions to Pakistan's nuclear program?",
      "options": [
        "Dr. Ishrat Hussain Usmani",
        "Dr. Abdul Sattar Edhi",
        "Dr. Abdul Qadeer Khan",
        "Dr. Atta-ur-Rahman"
      ],
      "correctOption": 2,
      "points": 20
    }
  ]
}
